so we've now gotten through all the
所以我们现在已经通过所有得到
lectures on machine code and we're
机器代码讲座和我们
starting to talk about okay now that you
开始谈论现在没事了，你
know this stuff what can you do with it
知道这东西有什么可以用它做什么
and this lecture is along the lines of
这讲座 沿行
that this is sort of what you are now
这是 那种 你现在 什么
empowered to do now that you can look at
授权现在你 可以看看 做
and understand machine code this
并理解机器码这
material is a little it's actually
材料是一 点点 ，它实际上
there's a whole chapter of the book
有本书的一整章
chapter 5 on performance optimization
在 性能优化 第 5 章
and we're only going to do one lecture
而我们只打算做一个讲座
on it and we don't have any labs
它和我们没有 任何实验室
unfortunately that really get you to
不幸的是，真正让你
push your limits on this which is too
把你的极限在这里面太
bad because it's a very interesting
不好，因为它是一个非常有趣的
topic and one I think you'd find
话题和一个我认为你会发现
yourself well equipped for there are
自己配备齐全，有
typically a few small exam problems that
通常是一些小考试的问题，
are sort of based on some of the
是那种基于一些
material here you'll find in old exams
材料在这里你会发现在旧考试
but really the idea is how can I make
但真正的想法 是如何才能让
programs run fast given that I sort of
程序跑得快给我几分
know what algorithm I'm using and I've
知道我使用的是什么算法，我已经
perhaps gotten a program that runs how
也许是得到运行程序如何
can I make it run faster and one of the
我可以让它运行 得更快和 的 一个
the themes of it is you can sort of do
它的主题是，你可以排序的做
this in layers you can sort of first of
这层可以排序 第一的
all do this stuff to avoid sort of
所有这样做的东西，以避免排序
things that make programs run slow
事情让程序运行缓慢
across a wide variety of machines and
跨多种设备和
just make your and I would describe it
只是让你 和我将之形容
as making your code more compiler
为使您的代码更编译
friendly and we'll talk about what that
友好，我们将谈论什么
means and you have to have some
意味着 你必须有一些
understanding and appreciation for what
理解和欣赏什么
compilers are good at and what they're
编译器善于和 他们是什么
not good at to be able to do that and I
不擅长，能够做到这一点， 我
describe these as the kind of things
描述这些作为样的东西
that you should just be in the habit of
你应该只是 在习惯
when you write programs writing this
当你写的程序写这
code that I'll describe is compiler
代码，我会形容为编译器
friendly and then the next level is okay
友好的，然后一个新的 水平是好的
given that I've sort of taken away the
因为我已经有点带走
things that really should have been
事情真的应该已经
there in the first place now how can I
有摆在首位，现在怎么可以
make my programs run faster in
让我的程序运行得更快
particular how can I adapt it to the
特别是我怎么能适应
capabilities of the the types of
该类型的能力
machines that this program
机，这个方案
going to run on and that can again go
要上运行，并能 再次去
from ones that will generally make
从那些通常会使
programs run fast across a wide variety
计划跨多种跑得快
of machines to ones that become very
机器的人 的 那个变得 非常
specific and very specific is a risky
具体的和非常具体是一个危险的
thing because even in the world of say
的事，因为即使是在世界上的发言权
x86 machines there's quite a variety of
x86上有很多种的
them that are available at any given
他们可在 任何给定
point in time and they evolve over time
在 时间点和它们随着时间的推移
as well so you can make a program run
还有 这样 你就可以使程序运行
really fast on one particular model of
对一个特定型号的真快
one x86 processor but it might not that
一个x86处理器，但可能无法在其
if you're trying too hard you'll find
如果你想太硬，你会发现
your effort is sort of wasted when you
你的努力是有点浪费，当你
move it to another on the other hand
它移动到另一个 ， 另一方面
these general ideas I'm going to
这些总体思路我要去
describe actually work across quite a
实际描述跨越相当工作
range of machines so and I'll talk about
机器的范围，这样，我就说说
that more as we go along so it used to
更多的 ，因为我们走，因此用于
be in the bad old days that if you
在坏日子，如果 你
wanted to program to run fast you had to
要 编程，运行速度快，你必须
write an assembly code and that's just
写汇编代码，这只是
plain not true anymore and if anyone
平原不再 成立了，如果有人
tells you it's true it's because they're
告诉你，这是真的 ， 那是 因为他们是
full of it it's just not true unless
充满了它，它只是不 除非 真
except for the exceptional case where
除特殊情况
you're running on a very small resource
你在一个非常 小的 资源 运行
constrained machine such as a very small
约束机如非常小的
underpowered embedded system so let's
动力不足的嵌入式系统等等，让我们
just assume that we're going to use a
只是假设， 我们将使用
compiler and we'll assume for this
编译器，我们将为此承担
course we're going to use GCC because
当然，我们要 使用GCC因为
it's generally available it's not
这是一般可用它不是
actually the best compiler out there
其实最好的编译器在那里
Intel makes a compiler that costs money
英特尔做一个编译器，它的成本钱
to license and stuff but it it really
它 真的 许可之类的东西，但它
can do some amazing things and other
可以做一些令人惊讶的事情 和其他
compilers exist but GCC is sort of a
编译器存在，但GCC是排序的
good enough compiler for most people
足够好的编译器对于大多数人
but there's some features of some things
但有一些事一些功能
that sort of puzzle compilers that they
那种拼图的编译器 ，它们
don't really understand compilers don't
真的不明白编译器不
really understand for example that the
真正理解例如，该
numbers you're using when you say it's
当你说你正在使用的号码是
an INT might actually range over a much
一个INT 实际上可能范围在更
smaller set of values and they have a
设置值越小，他们有一个
very hard time understanding memory
很很难理解 记忆
referencing patterns and the effect of
参考图案和效果
procedure calls
过程调用
and so in general what happens with the
所以一般用 什么 的 发生
compiler is it has a whole sort of
编译器是它有一个整体的排序
cookbook of optimization strategies and
的优化策略和食谱
some recipes for how to try out
一些食谱如何尝试
different strategies and apply them but
不同的战略和应用它们，但
in general if it ever feels like this
一般来说，如果它曾经感觉这
code is something that it doesn't feel
代码是什么，给人的感觉并不
confident about being able to make
自信能够做出
certain transformations but it just
某些变革，但它只是
won't it will keep things to a more
不会，将保持事情更
direct implementation of exactly what
直接执行的到底 是什么
you described and we'll show examples of
你描述的， 我们将展示 的 例子
that as we go along so the thing about
随着我们一起出去，这样的事儿
optimizing compilers it always has a
优化编译器总是有一个
fallback position which is to not
备用位置，这是不
optimize and sometimes that will get in
优化有时候会得到
trouble if you want your program to run
麻烦，如果你希望你的程序 运行
faster and the compiler just in its own
更快，编译器只是在自己的
conservative Y decides not to do that
保守Ÿ决定不 这样做
optimization and one of the tricks that
优化 和 技巧 的一个
you'll find is pretty useful now that
你会发现，现在，这是非常有用的
you can read assembly code is you run
您可以阅读汇编代码运行
the compiler you see what optimizations
编译器你看到了什么优化
it does and if it doesn't make something
它，如果它没有的东西
that you expect it to be able to do you
你希望它能够做到你
go back and figure it out so it's very
回去弄清楚 所以很
common by the way to rewrite your
通过改写的方式共同您
program in in the same language instead
程序在相同的语言，而不是
of tune it and up to make it run faster
调 并 达到使其运行速度更快
to make it more compiler friendly that
使其 更友好的编译器是
there's nothing wrong with that as long
有什么不妥 ，只要
as you don't then just totally
因为你不那么只是 完全
obliterate the program and make it
泯程序， 使它
totally illegible so let's just describe
完全无法辨认所以我们只描述
some sort of general optimizations and
某种一般的优化和
you've actually seen versions of this in
你亲眼看见 的 这个版本
some of the assembly code we've already
一些汇编代码 中 我们已经
looked at oh and I'll use mostly sort of
看着哦，我会主要使用排序
examples from multi-dimensional arrays
从多维数组的例子
because those are actually fairly easy
因为那些实际上是 相当容易
optimization type of tasks but these
任务，但这些优化类型
applied to other types of program as
应用于其它类型的程序作为
well so you saw before when we described
， 所以你当我们描述以前看到
how to do array indexing in
如何做数组索引 中
multi-dimensional arrays that the old
多维数组 ， 老
style of code was if you had a variable
的代码风格，如果你有一个变量
eyes array it was up to you the
眼睛阵列 是由你的
programmer to write the formula of how
程序员写 的如何式
you convert row I column J into a
您转换行我J列成
position in a one-dimensional array so
在一个 一维阵列 位置 ，从而
remember it's just the number of columns
记住它的列的 只是数
times the row number plus the column
次 行号加列
numbers standard one so that would give
数字标准之一，所以，会给
up this would be pretty typical code
了，这将是非常典型的代码
then it would give you a notation like
那就给你 喜欢 的符号
this if you wanted to set one rail row
这一点，如果你想设置一个轨排
in array a to the values in one
在在一个值阵列的
dimensional row of B this is the code
B的维的行是这样的码
you'd write and the main observation is
你会写，主要是观察
within this loop the only variable
这个循环的唯一变量内
that's changing is J and so from the
这就是变化为J，因此从
array perspective your this computation
阵列角度来看你的这种计算
n times I if it gets repeated over and
n次我，如果它被 不断地重复
over again within this loop then you're
一遍又一遍这个循环中，然后你
just wasting it's a wasted effort so you
只是在浪费这是浪费精力 ，所以你
can do what's called code motion which
可以做什么所谓的代码议案，
is to pre compute the value of n times I
是预先计算的n倍值I
outside of the loop and then use it over
循环 再使用外过来
and over again inside and compilers will
一遍又一遍 的内部和编译器会
generally do this when they can detect
通常这样做时，他们可以检测
for example that it's a array access
例如，它是一个数组访问
code and it has this technique it will
代码和它有这个技术， 它会
generally do optimizations like this if
一般做优化， 这样，如果
you set say an optimization level of 1
你设置要说1的优化级别
or higher to GCC and we can see this in
或更高GCC，我们可以在此看到
fact this is this code and I ran it
事实上， 这是该代码，我跑了
through GCC using optimization 1 and you
通过使用GCC优化 1，你
see as this read instruction shows it
看到因为这样 读指令显示它
boosted this multiplication outside of
推动这个乘法之外
the loop and it's a little as if you
循环并就好像你一点点
actually this code does even more it
其实这个代码更加 它
turns the code into something that looks
转码成的东西， 看起来
more like a pointer code accessing array
更像一个指针代码访问数组
a and stepping through that element by
和通过该元素通过步进
element of the array another one and
所述阵列另外一个元件和
we've seen this already that when GCC
我们已经看到了这个已经当GCC
turns a multiplication or division by
把一个乘法或除法由
shifting and AD
移位和AD
and operations like that multiplication
和这样的 乘法 运算
or division by constants
或者除以常数
we've seen an example to that and the
我们已经看到了一个 例子，说和
similar one would happen if if we took
如果，如果我们采取了类似一个会发生
that program I showed before and applied
那个节目我之前表现出与应用
it to every row so we want to set for
它的每一行，所以我们要设置其
array a we wanted to set every one of
数组我们要设定每一个
its rows to the value of the one
其行 之一的 值
dimensional array B then again if we we
维阵列乙然后再次，如果我们我们
took that code we boosted the end times
把这些代码我们提振了结束时间
I in there so now the inner loop is good
我在那里所以现在内环好
but you realize that this multiplication
但你知道，这个乘法
isn't necessary either because what
是没有必要的，因为无论是什么
we're doing from I equals 0 to I equals
我们从 我做等于0至我等于
1 to I equals 2 is we're just increasing
1至I等于2 是我们只是增加
the parameter ni by we're adding end to
参数 NI通过我们添加结束
it so we can and that's called a
它使我们能够而且这就是所谓的一
reduction in strength we've taken a
强度下降，我们已经采取了
multiplication and turned it into
乘法和把它变成
addition because there's some
此外，由于有一些
predictable pattern of how this variable
怎么这个变量的预测图案
ni is going to be updated another
NI将被更新的另一
example and again array indexing is a
例如，再次数组索引是
good example for optimizations imagine
好榜样的优化设想
we had a image that we represent as a
我们有我们代表作为一个图像
two-dimensional array of pixel values
像素值的二维阵列
and we want to do something that what a
我们想要做什么一个什么东西
filtering operation where we want to
过滤操作，我们要
take the sum of the four neighbors of a
采取的四个邻国的总和
given pixel north south east and west
给定像素南北东，西
and average those together or sum them
一起平均那些 或它们求和
together and so the natural way you'd
在一起， 所以 自然 的 方式，你会
write this and see is to say I want
写这篇文章，看看是说我想
usually in images you count from the top
通常在你的图像从顶部数
down and so you'd say this is the the
下来，所以你说这 是在
pixel above this is the pixel below this
上述该像素低于该像素
is the pixel to the left and this is the
是像素 的左边， 这是
pixel to the right and if you do this in
像素 ，如果你这样做是正确 的
and just compile it straight through
和公正编译直通
unfortunately it appears as if there's
不幸的是，看起来好像有
three different multiplication
三种不同的乘法
by n I minus 1 I plus 1 and I and if the
用n 我减1加我1， 我和若
compilers into clever it won't realize
编译器为聪明 也不会实现
that these are related to each other and
这些 都是相互关联的 ，并
it will issue three different multiply
它会发出三种不同的乘法
operations just to do this one pixel
操作只是做这一个像素
thing whereas if I'm a little more
事情而如果我多一点
clever and this is one where I manually
聪明，这是一个其中I手动
rewrote the code so the compiler would
重写了代码，所以编译器会
pick it up I'd say well if I on so I and
把它捡起来我会说好，如果我， 所以 我和
J is I times n plus J and I can get the
J是我N次加J和我可以得到
the pixel above the pixel below by
上述下方的像素由像素
shifting that off setting that by a
移该关闭设置，通过一个
value of n and then it will issue the
n个值，然后它会发出
code this will compile with the code
这个代码将与代码编译
with just one multiply and in general by
与只有 一个乘法和一般
the way it multiplied used to be a very
它 成倍 的方式 曾经是一个非常
expensive instruction nowadays is enough
昂贵的指令时下足够
hardware resources that it takes about
这大约需要硬件资源
three clock cycles so it's not a huge
三个时钟周期，所以它不是 一个巨大的
deal but anytime you can take three
交易，但任何时候 ，你可以采取三种
multiplies and use just one instead
乘法，并只使用一个替代
that's generally a good idea question so
通常是一个好主意， 这样的问题
the question is what if you're trying to
问题是，如果你 想 什么
optimize your space and there are a lot
优化 您的空间，也有很多
of optimizations that will make your
优化，这将使你的
code be bigger at the expense of in
代码是在更大的代价
order to go faster right
为了走得更快 权
this one though I'd argue this is
这一次，虽然我要说这是
actually shorter code right and just
实际上较短的代码正确和公正
look at the number of instructions so
看看指令数，从而
and usually so code you know that used
通常这样的代码，你知道使用
to be a bigger concern when memory was
是一个更大的问题时的记忆是
sort of you know back to the original
那种你知道回到 原
IBM PC had 640 kilobytes of memory so in
IBM PC有内存640千字节所以在
its maximum configuration and that was a
其最大的配置，这 是一个
big deal to actually buy it that much so
大不了实际购买那么远那么
you know back then that was a big deal
你知道 当时 这是 一个大问题
memory but nowadays memory that the size
记忆，但现在内存的大小
of the program is usually a pretty small
的程序通常是 一个非常 小的
fraction of what you're dealing with
你要处理什么用的分数
overall but it's a valid question
总体但它是一个 有效的问题
okay so that just shows you an example
好吧，这 只是给出了一个例子
and in general compilers are pretty good
和一般的编译器都还不错
at doing those low-level optimizations
在做这些 低级别的优化
like that if you write the code in a way
这样，如果你编写代码的 方式
that's reasonable but there's some other
这是合理的，但有一些其他
ones that the compiler and even a the
那些编译器，甚至在
fanciest compiler you can buy might not
你可以 买到 高档的编译器 可能不
be able to figure it out and so I like
能够计算出来 ， 所以我喜欢
to illustrate this with when the first
说明这与当第一
term we ever talked to thirteen I was
长期我们曾经聊到十三我
looking at some lab code that some of
看一些实验室代码，一些
the students wrote and I was horrified
学生写的，我被 吓坏了
about this code and I showed it to the
这段代码和我把它拿给
TAS and none of them figured out what
TAS 和他们没有想出什么
was wrong and I've shown it to many
是错的，我也出了许多
other highly-trained C programmers
其他训练有素的C程序员
professionals there we go looks okay to
专业人士那里我们去看起来还好
me so let's figure out what why I was
我让我们弄清楚我是什么原因
horrified by this code so the idea of
这段代码吓坏了这样的想法
this code is supposed to be pretty
这个代码 应该是 相当
straightforward there's a string s and I
简单有一个字符串s 和我
want to convert that string all the
希望该 字符串转换所有
characters in it to lowercase so I'm
在它字符转换为小写，所以我
just going to read through the string
刚刚经历的字符串读取
and for each string position test that
并且对于每个字符串的位置测试
character and if it's somewhere between
字符， 如果它是介于两者之间
upper case a and upper case Z then I'm
大写一个， 然后我上如果Z
going to shift it to being between
将它转移 到 之间
lowercase a and lowercase Z otherwise I
一个小写字母和小写ž否则我
will change it so pretty straightforward
将改变它， 非常简单
but if you run this you see that if you
但如果你运行这个 你看 ，如果你
go up to half a million characters which
上升到 五十万字，其
might sound like a lot but it takes 240
听起来好像很多 ，但它需要 240
or so so so four minutes to run this
或者这么这么这么 四分钟运行此
code and you go well that's a pretty big
代码和你去嗯 ，这是一个相当 大 的
string it's really not a big string you
字符串它真的不是 一个大的字符串你
should be able to do lowercase
应该能够做到小写
conversion of a string and a lot less
字符串转换少了很多
than four seconds and you also notice
超过 四秒，并同时发现
this growth is nonlinear it's quadratic
这种增长是非线性的是二次
it's growing as the square of the string
它的增长作为字符串的方
length so this is not good
长度，这是不好的
and unfortunately it's the kind and by
不幸的是它的种类和
the way this is one of the it's very
这种方式是对一个它是非常
easy surprisingly easy to have programs
易非常容易有计划
that have some hidden performance bug
有一些隐藏的参数错误
that makes them run quadratic and you
这使得它们运行的二次和你
run tests and you test for strings of
运行测试，你测试的字符串
of 10,000 or less and it doesn't look
10000以下，它看起来并不
like a big deal because the runtime is
什么大不了的 ，因为运行时间
insignificant so but then all of a
微不足道左右，但随后所有的
sudden it hits a really bad case so this
突然它击中一个非常糟糕的情况下，所以这
is a there's something wrong here so
是有什么东西错在这里 如此
what's so bad about this program well
什么是如此糟糕有关此计划以及
the key is went in a test like this of
关键是去在测试这样 的
calling sterlin so the way it's
调用sterlin所以它的方式是
determining whether it's reached the end
确定无论是走到了尽头
of the string is by calling sterlin to
字符串是通过调用sterlin到
figure out how long the string is and
找出串有多长和
the now and remember if we do the
现在记住，如果我们做的
conversion of a for loop into a go to
转换的for 循环 成细末，以
form like you've seen there's various
格式如您所看到有各种
ways to convert it but all of them the
方式转换，但所有 他们的
test gets built into the loop so the
测试被内置到循环使
main feature of that is this call to
那主要特征是这个调用
sterlin will happen every time you go
sterlin会发生每次你去的时间
through the loop and people overlook
通过循环 和人忽视
that fact when you look at the different
当你看这个事实的不同
parts of a for loop the initialization
for 循环 的初始化 的部分
only gets executed once but both the
只被执行一次，但无论是
test and the update get incremented get
测试 和更新获得递增的get
applied every time you run through the
应用每次通过运行时
loop so if that's getting called as many
循环 因此 ，如果这是越来越称为很多
times as there are characters in the
倍有字符在
loop in the string right and now how did
循环字符串中的权利，现在该怎么做
sterlin work remember and see the only
sterlin工作记忆和看到的唯一
way you know how long a string is is to
你 知道一个字符串是多么漫长的 道路 是
step through the whole thing and find
逐步通过整个事情，找到
the null character at the end so sterlin
在结束 这样sterlin空字符
itself is a linear time operation in the
本身是在一个线性时间的操作
string and you're doing that and so
字符串，你这样做等
you're doing end calls to a function
你在做最终调用一个函数
that takes time n the string is getting
这需要时间 n 串 越来越
shorter as you go but not very fast so
较短，当您去，但不是非常快 ，所以
basically that's quadratic performance
基本上这就是二次性能
and that explains why you get that
并解释为什么 你认为
runtime so in particular if I just make
运行时 如此特别 ，如果我只是做
the following little change I introduce
以下变化不大 我介绍
a local variable called Glen and I pre
一个局部变量叫格伦和我的预
compute sterlin because the string isn't
计算sterlin因为该字符串 不是
the length of the string isn't changing
字符串的长度没有改变
I'm just changing the characters in the
我只是改变的字符
string um then so the the program will
串嗯然后让程序会
do the same thing but now the runtime is
做同样的事情，但现在的运行时间
so short it doesn't even show up it's
那么短 ， 它 甚至 不 显示 它
it's maybe a second to do a million
这也许是第二次做一百万
characters it's just not a big deal at
字符它只是没有 什么大不了的
all as it should be it's just running
所有 理所应当的，它只是 运行
through and so that's just an example of
通过所以这只是一个例子
one of many that I've seen in my career
我在我的 职业生涯 见过很多之一
where something that that seems almost
这里的东西，似乎差不多
insignificant turns out to be a serious
微不足道的原来是 一个严重
performance problem so why couldn't a
性能问题，为什么 不能一
compiler figure this out why couldn't a
编译身影了这一点，为什么不能一
smart compiler look at the original code
智能编译器看原来代码
and say well you know this is what the
并说好，你 知道这是什么
programmer wrote but I know a better way
程序员写的，但我知道一个更好的办法
to do it I'll pre compute sterlin in
要做到 这一点，我会预先 在 计算 sterlin
advance whether there's a couple reasons
提前量是否有一对夫妇的原因
one is actually if you look at the code
一个 实际上 是 ，如果你 看一下代码
for sterlin you see that it's actually
为sterlin你看，它实际上
modifying the string and sterlin I mean
修改字符串和 sterlin我的意思
the the code here is modifying the
这里的代码修改
string and we're calling stern land on
字符串，我们呼吁严厉的土地
it so you'd have to be pretty careful to
它所以你必须非常小心
do the analysis the compiler would to
做了分析，编译器会以
figure out that even though the string
弄清楚， 即使串
is changing the result you're going to
正在改变你要的结果
get from sterlin is not going to change
从sterlin得到的是不会改变
right so that's a one reason and the
右所以这是 一个原因之一和
second is well and how do how does the
第二个是很好，怎么做怎么做的
can the compiler which version of
可以在编译器哪个版本的
sterlin is actually going to get used
sterlin实际上是要习惯
remember and see each of the files gets
记住，看到每个文件的获取
compiled separately and only afterwards
分开 和事后才 编译
does it all get brought together in the
所有这一切得到了汇聚
linking
链接
and some of that even happens after the
而一些即使以后发生
program get started so even though
节目开始 所以即使
there's a standard sterlin function it's
有一个标准sterlin功能，它是
not necessarily the case that that's the
不一定是这样的 情况
one that will actually get used in the
一个将实际 的习惯
final program so the compiler really
最后的程序，以便编译器真的
can't be sure of that
不能肯定的说
in particular imagine I provided a sort
特别是想象我提供了一个排序
of customized sterlin function like this
像这样的 定制 sterlin 功能
that is keeping track of the sum of the
这是保持党 的 总和轨道
lengths of all the strings that it's
所有它的字符串长度
been called on or some other side effect
被称为上或其他一些副作用
like that that well that that program
这样的那么好，即这项 方案
would produce a very different result
会产生非常不同的结果
than if if I whether or not I make the
如果不是，如果我是否我做
optimization so the compiler has to
优化，因此编译器必须
assume that sterlin is just a black box
假设sterlin仅仅是一个黑盒子
that does whatever it does and can't
，做任何它 并不能
make any assumptions about what how what
对什么 任何假设 怎么样
side effects it might have and so forth
副作用，它可能有 等等
so it won't make that optimization on
所以它不会 对最优化
any machine
任何机器
even with the best compiler so that's
即使有最好的编译器，这是
just an example that and you can tell
只是一个 例子，你可以告诉
that I've gotten kind of sensitized to
我已经得到了一种致敏
this so that I spot these but a lot of
这让我发现这些只是很多
people don't um so let's look at this
人不嗯让我们看看这个
let's see oh this is another bad example
让我们看看哦，这是另一个坏榜样
a bad coding example of imagine I want
不好的编码例想象我想
to compute for a two-dimensional array a
来计算二维 阵列的
in a one-dimensional array B I want to
在一个 一维阵列 BI要
make B be B sub I be the sum of of all
做B时B子我是所有 的总和
the elements in row I of a so again this
在 一 排 我 的元素 ，因此这一次
is a fairly obvious kind of way to write
是一个相当明显的 一种方式来写
this program that you say well B I cook
这个程序，你说好 BI厨师
0 and I'm going to just accumulate it
0和我要去只是它积累
I'll step through the row and accumulate
我将逐步行和积累
all the values and of course we know now
所有的价值，当然，我们现在知道
we could improve this by moving I times
我们可以通过移动i次提高该
n out and so forth I'm not trying to
N OUT等等，我并不想
illustrate that
说明
but what you'll see in the program this
但你会在节目中看到这
is in the inner loop and we'd look
是在内部循环，我们想看看
briefly at some floating-point
简单一些浮点
instructions and remember that the main
说明和注意主
feature of them is the move instructions
他们的特点是移动指令
look like the move ones you're familiar
像移动那些你熟悉
with except when we we put
与除非我们我们把
floating-point data in one of these xmm
在这些XMM之一浮点数据
registers so the main thing you see here
寄存器，这样你在这里看到的主要的事情
is it's reading from memory it's adding
是它从内存中读取 它的加入
something to it and then it's writing
东西，然后将它的 写作
back to memory and what that memory
回到内存 ，什么内存
location corresponds to B of I so what
位置对应于I B等什么
it means is every time through this loop
它通过这个循环意味着每一次
it's having to do a memory read and a
它不必做读 存储器和
memory write of B in addition to the
除了 B的存储器写
memory read of a even though presumably
内存读取，即使可能的
B of AI is the same of value that you
AI的B 是相同的值，可以
just updated it to out in the previous
只是把它更新到 了在前面
execution of this loop right so why do
这个循环的执行权 ，为什么做
you have to why do you read it why do
你要为什么你读它，为什么
you write it out and then read it back
你写出来， 然后读回
in increment it and then again copy it
在增量，然后再复制它
back out why does it have to go keep
背出它为什么 去保持
jumping back and forth between memory
来回跳跃内存之间
and registers over and over again
并注册 了一遍又一遍
well the reason is because in C you
良好的原因是因为在C你
can't be sure that there isn't what's
不能肯定有没有什么
known as aliasing and I'm demonstrating
被称为混叠，我演示
it here imagine if row B is just
在这里想象一下，如果B行只是
declared to be that ok so imagine and
声明是 确定，所以想象 和
you can do this in C this is legal C
你可以做这在 C，这是合法的C
code you can make one memory data
代码， 你可以做一个内存中的数据
structure overlay another data structure
结构覆盖另一数据结构
that's referred to as aliasing when two
这所指的内容混淆当两个
separate parts of the program are
该程序的分开的部分是
referring to the same locations in
指的是在相同的位置
memory and the C compiler has no way of
内存和C编译器 已经没办法了
knowing whether there's a lot of work
知道是否有大量的工作
and optimizing compilers to detect
和优化编译器来检测
racing possibilities but in general as
赛车可能性，但一般般
to assume aliasing might happen so
假设混叠可能 因此 发生
imagine this aliasing happened so that
想象这发生混淆 ，使
array B can correspond to them to this
阵列B可与它们对应于这
row of array a
阵列的行的
well then of course its initial value is
井那么当然它的初始值是
four eight sixteen but if you trace
四后八 16，但如果你追踪
through what this code will do it has a
通过什么这个代码将做到这一点有
sort of odd behavior that is probably
那种奇怪的行为可能是
not useful for anything but it just
不是任何有用的东西，但它 只是
demonstrates that what will happen is as
表明 会发生什么是
this as B gets updated it's effectively
此为B得到更新它的 有效
changing a and it's changing then what's
改变和它的变化，然后什么
being read during the summation and so
求和等过程中被读取
this is a real possibility in C and so
这是C等一种现实的可能性
the compiler when it's given code like
当它给 像代码 编译器
this it has to assume that the these two
这一点， 必须假定这两个
memory locations might court overlap
内存位置可能重叠告上法庭
each other so that's why it's carefully
对方所以这就是为什么它是仔细
writing it out and then reading it back
写出来，然后回读
in over and over again and so if I just
在一遍又一遍，因此 ，如果我只是
rewrite this code by introducing again a
通过 再次引入一个 重写这个代码
local variable and accumulating in that
局部变量和在该累加
local variable and then only at the end
仅 在端部 的局部 变量，然后
do I sign that to B sub I then you'll
我签署到B子我那么你会
see this exact same loop all of a sudden
看到此相同循环突然
gets a lot simpler it's just a read
得到了很多简单的，它只是一个读
floating point read an ad to do that and
浮点 读的广告做到这一点，
we'll see in fact the memory is actually
我们其实看到内存实际上是
one of the limiting of perform
限制的执行的一个
performance limiters in a program so
在程序的性能限制等等
this is will be significantly faster and
这是快速地将是显著和
again that's something that you as a
再次在这个时候，你作为一个
programmer would hardly think is a big
程序员将很难 认为这是一个很大的
deal but the C compiler can't do that in
交易，但C编译器不能做，在
general because it can't determine in
一般的，因为它不能确定
advance what possible aliasing there can
推进什么可能的混淆可以有
be
是
so these two examples say so to get in
所以这两个例子这么说来获得
the habit of introducing local variable
引入局部变量的习惯
and using them and it's your way of
并使用它们，那是你的方式
telling the compiler don't call the same
告诉编译器 不会调用相同
function over and over again don't read
功能翻来覆去不读
and write the same memory location over
并在写同一个内存位置
and over again just hold it in the
一次又一次地只是 将其保持 在
temporary one and then it will
暂时的，然后它会
automatically allocate a register and
自动分配的寄存器和
store it in that register and everything
其存储在寄存器和一切
will be good okay so that's sort of the
将是很好的好，这样的排序的
the kind of what we call optimization
那种我们称之为优化
blockers the kind of things that you as
阻滞剂样的事情 ，你作为
a programmer can make a difference on
程序员可以做出差异
and the main blockers are memory
和主阻滞剂是存储器
referencing aliasing and function calls
引用别名和函数调用
and sort of understanding what might
和体悟 什么可能
happen in that function call and so now
所以现在发生在函数调用
what we're going to do is transition
我们要做的是转变
questions
问题
I think you make the distinction between
我认为你做的区别
no no this is Alan C code I'm sure this
不，不，这是 艾伦·C代码我敢肯定，这
is LC code because it ran so this is
是LC的代码，因为它跑了，所以这是
initializing calling it an array B
初始化调用它的阵列乙
remember these are in stars these aren't
记住这些都是在恒星这些都不是
two-dimensional arrays right so this is
二维阵列权，所以这是
saying a is now a think of it as a
话说现在是一个把它看作一个
linear array of four elements of nine
九个四个元件的线性阵列
elements and a plus three is just to go
元素和一个加三就是 去
in three so this is it is declaring B is
在三个所以这是它被宣称B是
not a pointer it's an array but remember
不是指针它是一个数组，但请记住
with an array you can refuse that the
一个数组，你 可以拒绝 该
name of that array as a reference to a
该数组作为对基准的命名
pointer a readable reference not a
指针可读参考不是
writable reference right right for this
写参考对对这个
well so the question is why does he use
也因此， 问题是， 他 为什么要 使用
null terminated strings and it it does
空终止字符串，它确实
and it might be a bad decision for
它可能是一个错误的决定
multiple reasons right but I think in
多种原因的权利，但我认为 ， 在
general think of C was somebody who had
的C一般想到的就是别人谁了
or a couple people who had been writing
或一对夫妇的人 谁曾写
a lot of assembly code and wanted to
大量的汇编 代码 ，并希望
lift up that level so they weren't
提起这个水平，所以他们不
writing the same stuff over and over
一遍又一遍地写相同的东西
again but not thinking in terms of how
再次但是在 如何思维
can I be the most abstract possible so
我可能是最抽象可能使
they were trying to provide sort of a
他们试图提供种类的
minimum layer on top of machine level
上机级的顶部的最小层
programming that would let them write
编程，将让他们写
code that could run from one machine to
，可以运行 从一台机器代码
another so in everything they do they
另一个所以在一切他们做自己
sort of use the most simple
那种用最简单的
representation and don't assume any kind
表示不承担任何 种类
of there's no array of you know most
的有没有数组的你知道最
languages
语言
would have array bounds checking and
将有数组边界检查和
array would be a data structure that
阵列将是一个数据结构， 其
would include its size you know range of
将包括它的大小，你所知道的范围内
values and stuff and see just doesn't so
价值观和东西，看到的只是不那么
everything about see is suit at the
对看到的一切都是 西装在
minimum and you know it's been around
最低限度， 你知道它的存在了
for a 40 or something years so no Pascal
对于 40 年的东西所以没有帕斯卡尔
does not proceed see no as simply not
不继续看不出是根本就没有
true Pascal was created as a language
真正帕斯卡尔被创造了作为一门语言
for teaching by the SONA and Nicko
由SONA和力高的教学
spirit and it was very much an
精神，这是非常多的
instructional language so it was really
教学语言，所以这是真的
designed to help students who needed
旨在帮助 谁需要 学生
help and c was designed by professional
帮助和 c是由专业的设计
programmers to let them write their code
程序员，让他们编写代码
and not get in their way so they're very
在他们的方式没有得到让 他们感到 非常
different theory between the two
两者之间的不同理论
languages right yes
语言对是
what's that I'm sorry F oh yes that's a
那是什么对不起˚F哦，是的，这是一个
mistake there I'll double-check this or
错误那里 我会 仔细检查 这 或
people could check it I'm pretty sure
人们可以检查 它，我敢肯定
this code is okay too
这个代码是好 太多
if not you can certainly say double star
如果没有可以肯定地 说双星
B equals a plus three and that would
B等于一加三和会
work right question you think what
工作的权利问题，你怎么看
you think this is 28 well I'm not going
你认为这是28家我不会
to try in hand execute it here but let's
尝试在手在这里执行它，但让我们
check it you and I will check this code
检查一下你，我会检查这个代码
out and we'll fix it if it needs to be
出来， 如果它 需要 我们修复它
fixed okay thanks for pointing it out
固定好感谢指点出来
yeah no that doesn't make any difference
是啊 不，不作任何区别
at all in this code no know where it's
在这段代码根本不 知道它的
allocated makes no difference at all
分配没有什么区别可言
here so I'll check that might have to be
在这里，所以我会检查 可能是
double star B equals 8 plus 3 but I this
双星B等于8 + 3， 但我这个
was a while ago that I wrote this code
是前一阵子， 我写了这个代码
out double check it though okay so
出来仔细检查它虽然 好了，
anyways that's the sort of end of the
反正这是排序的结束
story for for a simple simple optimist
故事一个简单简单的乐观主义者
and they are simple optimizations it's
他们是简单的优化它的
just you have to give them a habit of
只是你必须给他们的一种习惯
doing it okay now what we're going to do
没事做， 现在我们要做的
is go a little bit fancier than this and
是去比这个票友一点点，
as I said this becomes somewhat more
我说，这变得有效
system dependent but pretty much
系统相关的，但相当多
nowadays all processors are have similar
现在， 所有的处理器都具有相似的
implementation they all do what's known
实现他们都做什么是已知的
as out of order execution except for the
作为乱序 执行 除的
most primitive microcontrollers and so
最原始的微控制器等
this is a kind of optimization oh so
这是一种优化的哦，所以
you'll find well this general approach
你会发现 好这个一般方法
will work across quite a variety of
将跨很多种的工作
machines so what I'm going to do is is
机器还等什么，我要做的就是为
do this by a series of example starting
通过启动一系列例子做到这一点
from some not very efficient code and
一些不是很高效的代码和
making it run faster and faster and
使其运行 速度更快， 更快，
we'll get a speed-up of around 40 just
我们将得到的40左右的速度向上只是
in doing what we're doing so it all
在做什么，我们正在这样做这 一切
starts by saying well assume I have a
说好假设我 有一个 开始
data structure that looks like the way
数据结构， 看起来像的方式
Pascal influenced arrays sorry I have
帕斯卡尔影响阵列抱歉，我有
nothing against Pascal
并不反对帕斯卡尔
we used to teach it back in the old days
我们曾经教过它回到过去
but so a typical way you'd implement an
但这样一个典型的方式，你会实施
array in a language is you'd provide
阵列中的语言是你提供
both the values that are stored in that
既存储在这些值
array and then there'd be other
阵列再有会是其他
information associated with it for
与 它 相关联的信息
example what size it is and so this is
例如什么尺寸是所以这是
sort of the sort of nice abstract way to
排序排序的漂亮抽象的方式来的
do it and you write code that makes sure
做到这一点，你写的代码 ， 确保
that if you ever try to exceed the
如果你曾经尝试超越
bounds on the array you'd return an
阵列上的边界你 返回
error signal and so this particular
误差信号等这个特定
function you're seeing is what I want to
工作，你看到的是什么， 我想
retrieve an element I passed an appoint
找回我通过一个元素的任命
and then that value the pointer gets
然后该值的指针变
used to retrieve the value from the
用于检索从价值
array and the return value of this
阵列和 的这个 返回值
function is then to 0 or 1 0 meaning
功能是 再到0或1 0含义
failure in one meaning success and I'm
失败的一个意义的成功，我
writing it this way that I use a data
写作是这样，我用数据
type I'll call data underscore T and
键入我会打电话数据强调了T 和
that way I can run this I can compile
这样我可以运行这个我可以编译
this code using different definitions of
该代码使用不同的定义
data underscore T to get in long floats
数据强调T对长期浮动获得
and doubles and we'll see how the
和双打，我们将看到怎样的
performance characteristics are those
性能特点是那些
shift with the different data types and
用不同的数据类型和移位
the benchmark I'm going to use is a
我将使用的基准是
fairly simple one it's just to for a an
相当简单的一个 ，它只是 给 了一个
array or one of these vectors
阵列或这些矢量中的一个
I just want to combine all the elements
我只是想所有的 元素结合
of it either compute their sum or their
它无论是计算它们的和或
product and again I'm going to use
产品，再次我要 使用
macros here ident and up and define
宏这里 的ident及以上，并确定
those so that op is addition and the
那些使得op是加法和
identity value is 0 where I the OP is
同一性值是0，其中我的OP是
multiplication and the identity element
乘法 和单位元
is 1 so that I can compare addition and
1，这样我可以比较加法和
multiplications so that gives us sort of
乘法，从而使我们的排序
eight possibilities here two different
这里八种可能性两个不同
operations in four different data types
在四个不同的 数据类型的 操作
and so this is written in the sort of
所以这是写在 那种
most straightforward manner that I'm
最简单的方式，我是
using this function called get BEC
使用该功能名为get BEC
element to retrieve the successive
元件来检索连续
values of this array and then performing
此数组的值，然后执行
its operation on it so now to express a
其上操作所以现在来表达
performance of this we're going to use a
这种表现，我们要使用一个
metric I introduced called CPE which
公制我引入了一个名为CPE 这
stands for cycles per element and the
代表每个元素和周期
idea is that usually when you write code
想法是，通常当你写代码
that say steps through effect anything
这说通过什么效果步骤
that has sort of some linear performance
有排序的一些线性性能
as you get bigger you don't really want
当你长大了，你真的不希望
to know for exactly it takes this many
要知道 它 到底 借此很多
seconds or microseconds or nanoseconds
秒或微秒或纳秒
to do an operation you kind of want to
做你有种 想 操作
know often more what's its overall
知道往往更什么是它的整体
performance characteristics and also it
性能 特点并且还
turns out when you're doing low-level
原来，当你做低级别
code optimization it's much more useful
代码优化它的有用得多
to think in terms of clock cycles of the
想在 的 时钟周期计算
inner clock of the processor rather than
该处理器的内时钟而不是
an absolute term such as nanoseconds
绝对的术语如纳秒
because whether a processor is running
因为处理器是否正在运行
at two gigahertz through 2.3 gigahertz I
在 两千兆赫至2.3千兆赫的我
don't really I have no control over that
真的不我过，没有控制
as a programmer but I can control sort
作为一个程序员，但 我能控制
of it the low-level how many clock
它的低层次的多少时钟
cycles are being used for different
周期被用于不同
parts of the computation so that's why
计算的部分 所以这就是为什么
it's called cycles per element and you
这就是所谓的每个元素和你的周期
can think of it as and this shows some
可以把它看成，这表明一些
actual measurements that typically a
实际测量， 通常一
function like this get what I showed the
像这样的功能得到了我的表现
combined will have some overhead a fixed
合并将有一些开销 固定
amount that's associated with setting up
这与建立相关的量
the loop doing the top level call and
循环做顶级呼叫，
all that stuff and then some components
所有的东西，然后一些部件
that's linear in the size and so what I
这是线性的大小等我
want to know is the scope of that linear
想知道的是，线性范围
components I'll and that will determine
组件 我会和这将决定
that's what I'll call the cycles per
这就是我会打电话给 每个周期
element you can think of the scope is
你能想到的范围元素
the sort of incremental cost of adding
排序 增加的增量成本的
one more element to the array
一个更元件到 所述阵列
so now if I run this function I showed
所以现在如果我运行 这个功能 我发现
you and I'm only showing I'll mostly
你，我只显示 我主要
only show four results because it turns
只显示四个结果，因为它变成
out whether it's int or long or float or
它是否是int或长或浮或
double is not going to actually have any
双是不会真正有什么
effect on performance for most of the
性能对于大多数的效果
cases so if I just run this code through
这样的情况下，如果我只是通过运行此代码
a compiler and don't do any
一个编译器，不要做任何
optimizations it takes around 20 cycles
优化它需要大约20 个循环
per element and if I turn on
每个元素，如果我打开
optimization level 1 which is sort of
优化级别 1，它是有点
the first serious optimization it takes
它需要先认真优化
the time in half so I'm down to 10 clock
在半所以我到 10个时钟时间
cycles per element just by changing the
每个元素的周期仅通过改变
compilation and that jeezum the most
编译和jeezum最
unoptimized code I could think of here
未经优化的代码，我能想到的在这里
and then I won't go through it all but
然后我不会去通过这 一切，但
using sort of the kind of things I
使用排序的那种东西我
described earlier of sort of cut away
前面所描述的那种切掉
some of the redundancy in this program
一些冗余的这一方案
you can get it down to something a
你可以得到它下来 的东西
little bit simpler and so one thing
有点简单 ， 这么一 件事
instead of you saw before I was making a
而不是你看到的 我是在 之前
call to this get deck element and every
调用此获取 deck元素，每
time it did that it went bounds checking
火候做它去边界检查
and it's kind of silly to keep bounds
并且它是一种愚蠢的 ，以保持边界
checking the same array over and over
反复检查同一阵列
again when I'm stepping I'm using its
当再次声明，我踩着我使用它
length as the determinate of how many
长度多少的 定
elements to access so if I'm willing to
元素来访问，所以如果我愿意
to to forgo balanced checking what I can
到 放弃的平衡检测我所能
do is introduce a function that will
做的是引入一个函数，将
just give me the actual data storage
只要给我实际的数据存储
part of this vector and skip over all
这种载体的一部分，并跳过所有
the other stuff and so I can write a
其他 的 东西 ，所以我可以写一个
loop it and I introduce you know local
循环它， 我介绍你了解当地
variables and all the kind of things we
变量和所有的那种东西 ，我们
described and accumulate in temporaries
描述并在累积的临时
and things like that then the program
之类的东西，然后程序
actually gets a lot faster again with
实际上 更快地再次 得到了很多 与
this is everything from here out is
这是一切从这里走出IS
optimization level 1 and so it drops it
优化级1等抛弃它
down to a little over a clock cycle for
下降到略高于 时钟周期
integers addition of or three clock
整数添加或三个时钟
cycles up to 5 clock cycles through
周期最多5个时钟周期通过
double precision multiplier
双精度乘数
so that's pretty good I've sort of
所以这是相当不错的我已经有点
definitely improved things but the
有了一定的提高，但事情的
question is well is that the best there
问题是好是最好有
is
是
and first and also try to understand
和第一， 也试着去了解
what is it about these numbers 3 5 and
是什么样的，这些数字 3和5
this seems to be something close to 1.25
这似乎有什么东西接近 1.25
so where those numbers coming from and
那么， 从 未来 这些 数字 和
does that indicate some fundamental
这是否表明一些基本
limitation in my program well in order
在我的计划不仅限于以及为了
to do that you have to have some
要做到这一点，你必须 有一些
understanding of the underlying hardware
底层硬件 的理解
and there's a really good course you can
并有一个非常好的当然你也可以
take I think it's called ECE 741 so it
拿我认为， 这就是所谓的 ECE 741所以
will tell you everything you ever could
会告诉你， 你都做不到的一切
imagine wanting to know about processor
想像想 知道关于处理器
design and you actually design
设计和你实际设计
processors like this but I'm assuming
处理器是这样，但我假设
you're not going to do that for a while
你不打算这样做 了一段时间
because if you have about seven
因为如果你有大约七
prerequisites to do before that happen
先决条件于 发生 之前做
so let me just give you the simple
所以让我给 你简单
version and Vincents sort of a an idea
版本和文森不大不小的一个想法
of what a processor has looked like
一个什么样的处理器已经长得很像
since about 1995 so this is old stuff
自1995年左右，所以这是旧的 东西
but it's enough actually to really
但它足以实际上 真正
understand it it's so hard it's really
理解它是如此难以它真的
the details are pretty massive and so
细节是相当 巨大的，因此
it's not even taught for example 447 is
它甚至没有教示于例如 447
the ECE is the computer architecture
在ECE是计算机架构
course and they don't really go into
当然，他们并不真正进入
this kind of design here because they're
这种 设计在这里，因为他们
pretty hard they're actually hard to
相当困难的，他们实际上是很难
design on your own but the basic idea is
设计你自己的，但其基本思想是
you think about a program as is the
你想想一个程序一样是
computer just reads in an instruction
电脑只是读取指令
does whatever it says to do reads in
做什么它说做读取
another instruction does what that says
另一个指令做什么，说
to do and that has nothing to do with
这样做并没有任何与
how programs actually execute what
程序实际上是如何 执行的是什么
they've built up is this massive
他们已经建立起来的是这个庞大的
hardware infrastructure to make a
硬件基础设施来进行
program run way faster than it would if
程序运行方式 会比如果快
it were just doing one instruction at a
它只是做一条指令
time and it employs a technique that's
时间，它采用 了一种技术，是
called superscalar out of order
所谓的超标量乱序
execution and the idea is roughly
执行和想法 大致
speaking it it takes your program if you
讲它需要你的程序，如果你
think of your program as a linear
想你的程序作为一个线性
sequence of instructions and it just
指令序列，它只是
sucks in as many of those as it can
吸入尽可能多的，因为它可以
and it pulls it apart to realize that
并将其拉它除了要认识到
certain operations don't really depend
某些操作真的不依赖
on each other so I can start one even
彼此 ，所以我 可以甚至开始一个
though later in the program
虽然后来在节目
then the one I'm working on right now
那么一个我的工作， 现在
because they're independent of each
因为它们是相互独立的
other and it's extracting what they call
其他和它的提取他们所称
instruction level parallelism places
指令级并行的地方
where even though your program is a
其中， 即使你的程序是
linear sequence of instruction buried in
埋在指令的线性序列
there is actually a sort of forest of
居然还有几分森林
different computations that need to be
需要不同的计算
done some which depend on each other and
做了一些 依赖于对方，
some which don't and then it has a bunch
一些不然后有一堆
of hardware and so that's up here this
硬件，所以这里这个是向上
upper part shows this idea of fetching
上半部分显示了这个想法取的
instruction so there's a cache memory a
指令，以便有一个高速缓冲存储器
high performance high speed local memory
高性能高速本地内存
that is just pulling in your
这只是拉着你的
instructions as fast as it can and those
尽可能快，因为它可以和这些指令
instructions are then feeding a big pile
指令接着喂一大堆
of hardware that will extract out of it
硬件将提取出来
these low-level operations and figure
这些低级别操作和数字
out which ones depend on which others
出哪些取决于哪个人对
and then the there is a set of
再有一组
functional units in this part of it that
在这部分内容 在于功能单元
are able to perform these low-level
能够执行 这些低级
operations to do arithmetic
操作做算术
floating-point operations to read data
浮点运算读取数据
from memory to store data back to memory
从存储器来存储数据回 存储器
all using a cache which is something
所有使用缓存这是 一件好事
you're going to learn about fairly soon
你要 很快就会 了解
out what all this cache is but think of
什么这一切缓存，但想到
this as a high speed copy of some of the
的一些以此为高速拷贝
data memory and um and so what this this
数据存储和 UM还等什么这个这个
logic tries to do is keep up forking out
逻辑试图做的就是继续向上分叉
spawning off operations based on your
产卵关操作根据您的
program and keeping these as busy as
程序和保持这些一样忙碌
they can be doing different fragments of
他们可以做的 不同 片段
your code doing different instructions
你的代码做不同的指令
in a different order from before and it
从与之前不同的顺序
turns out you think of a register as a
原来你认为寄存器作为
little the set of registers is a part of
小该组寄存器是的一部分
memory that gets read and written it
这被读取和写入内存它
turns out that in executing a register
原来，在执行寄存器
now just becomes the name
现在只要成为该名称
of something that one instruction
的东西，一个指令
produces and some other instructions
生产和一些其它指令
consume it's the destination for some
消耗它的一些目标
it's the source for others and this
它是为他人而这个源
whole a bunch of stuff here just sort of
整了一堆东西在这里只是有点
magically passes the results of one
神奇传递之一的结果
computation to the input to another
计算以输入到另一个
computation based on register names
基于寄存器的名称计算
without ever storing them in the and a
而没有将它们存储在 和
explicit register file there is a
明确的寄存器文件存在
register file when things kind of settle
寄存器文件，当事情 样的解决
down they get stored away anyways
下来，他们得到反正存储起来
there's a lot of stuff going on here but
有很多东西怎么回事，但
the main thing to think about is your
考虑主要的 是你的
machine has resources to do multiple
该机 拥有的资源 做多
operations all at the same time if you
操作都在同一 时间 ，如果你
can somehow structure your program so
能以某种方式构建程序 等等
that those can all get used so this is
这些都可以习惯，所以这是
as I mentioned it's called a superscalar
正如我所说这就是所谓的超标
instruct processor is one that can do
指示处理器是一个可以做
more than one instruction every clock
以上 每个时钟 一条 指令
cycle and actually Intel's started in 93
周期，实际上英特尔在93开始
the very first pentium could do two
最先奔腾可以做两
instructions at once but then a little
在一次指令，但随后一点点
later they came out with one called the
后来他们想出了 一个叫
Pentium Pro which is sort of the basis
Pentium Pro的是 排序依据
of all modern processors and the lead
所有现代处理器和领先的
architect by the way was a CMU graduate
建筑师的方式是CMU毕业
but this out order execution is the
但这种乱序执行 的是
model that's used nowadays so the other
多数民众赞成采用 了时下所以其他 模型
thing is those functional units are more
就是这些功能单元都比较
complex than you think they might be in
复杂得多， 你 认为他们可能会 在
that they have what's called pipelining
他们有什么所谓流水线
and the ideas of pipelining is imagine
和流水线的想法是 想象
you can break up a computation into a
你可以分解计算成
series of distinct stages a simple
一系列不同的阶段简单的
example is if you want to compute a
例子是，如果 你想 计算
times B plus C you first do the times
乘以B加C，你先做倍
and then you do the plus but it actually
然后你做的加号，但它实际上
gets more than that you can take
得到更重要的是，你可以采取
something like multiplication and break
像 乘法和休息
it up into smaller steps that can be
成更小 的步骤， 可以
done one after the other in a way that
做 的 方式 一 前 一 后 说
and then if you have a separate
然后，如果你有一个单独的
dedicated Hardware for each of those
专用硬件为每个的
stages then you can do it called
阶段，那么你可以做到这一点叫
pipelining which is when one operation
流水线这是当一个操作
moves from one
从一个移动
the stage to the next a new operation
舞台下一个新的操作
can come in behind and start started
可以进来后面开始启动
thing so this example shows imagine I
的事情，所以这个例子说明我想象
had a three stage pipeline multiplier
有一个三阶段的流水线乘法器
and I want to do this computation a
我想这样做计算的
times B a times C and now multiply those
次B A倍C和现在相乘那些
together so the thing to observe is that
在一起，使 观察的是，
a times B and a times C don't depend on
一时间B与C时代不依赖于
each other in any way so I can do them
对方以任何方式，所以我可以做他们
both and I don't have hardware to do
既和我没有做硬件
them simultaneously but I have them
他们同时但我有他们
enough to do one right after the other
够对方后做一个正确的
so I can feed the first computation into
所以我可以养活第一计算成
the first stage a times B on step times
上步骤 倍第一阶段a倍 乙
step one and then times step two it will
步骤之一，然后次第二步它会
move on to stage two and times step
转移到第二阶段和时间步骤
three it will move on to stage three but
三颗，将进入第三阶段 ，但
now I can start a times C in the time
现在我可以在时间开始C时代
step two because this stage became
步骤二，因为这个阶段开始
available once a times B moved from
可一次次B，从移动
stage one to stage two and so I can
第一阶段到 第二阶段，所以我可以
follow right behind just one clock cycle
遵循正确的背后只是一个时钟周期
behind this other operation now P times
这背后的其他操作现在 P次
one times p2 obviously depends on both
一个 时代 P2显然取决于 两个
of these products so it can't start
这些产品，因此无法启动
until a times C is completed and then it
直到C时代结束，然后
will run through the pipeline without
将通过管道进行，而不
anything else
别的
so overall then we've done what would
所以总体那么我们所做的事会
normally seem to be nine steps worth of
通常似乎是九步价值
arithmetic in a total of seven steps
算术共有七个步骤
here because of pipelining question
这里，是因为管道问题
with it if he had like in this is a
它如果他有像 这 是一个
picture here if there were different
图片浏览，如果有不同
multipliers in these different places
在这些不同的地方乘数
yes you could do those two completely
是的，你可以做这两个完全
independent of each other yes this is
相互独立是的，这是
all in a single core of a single
都在一个单一的单核
processor multi-core is yet another this
处理器多核是又一此
is a lower level parallelism than you
比你低级别的并行
get through multi-core and it's present
通过多核获得， 它的存在
except in the sort of lowest end lowest
除了在那种 最低端的最低
power and embedded processors some
功率和嵌入式处理器的一些
version of this exists and most of the
这个版本存在， 大部分的
time your hardware is not being fully
时间你的硬件没有被完全
utilized it's one thing you're going to
利用它的一两件事你要
learn from this so that's the idea
学习一下，这样的 想法
pipelining it it's a sort of like
流水线它这是一个有点像
parallelism but it's not that you have
并行，但它不是，你有
multiple copies of resources it's that
资源的多个副本 ，它是
you have this ability to stream
你有这个能力，以流
operations through a single Hardware
通过一个单一的 硬件 操作
resource in quotes exception to each
资源引号例外各
other and so as well which is a little
其他等等，以及这是 一个小
bit more recent than the sharp machines
位 比 大幅机 更 近
but not that much more is one of the
但不是说更是一
most recent versions of the Intel x86
最近英特尔的x86版本
series and the functional units include
系列和功能单元包括
oh there's a lot of functional units
哦，有很多的 功能 单元
that can do different things but when
可以做不同的事情，但是当
you add it all up there's a possibility
你说 起来还有一种可能性
of it doing two loads in one store for
它做两个负载在一个商店
integer operations two floating-point
整数运算两个浮点
multiplies one addition and one division
乘以一个加法和一个师
of they can't all happen at the same
他们不可能都发生在同一
time because there's some are shared
时间，因为有一些 共享
functional units but the point is
功能单元但问题是
there's really a lot of equipment there
没什么很多 的设备有
that can do stuff
可以做的东西
and also you can measure how an
也可以测量一个如何
instruction now has two characteristics
现在的指令有两个特点
and operation is how long does it take
经营多久没有考虑
from beginning to end but also how
从开始到结束，但怎么也
closely spaced can to interoperate be
紧密间隔开的可互操作是
because of this pipelining so you see
因为这个管道，所以你看到的
that most of them take some number of
他们大部分采取 的 一些数
clock cycles to perform but they're also
时钟周期来执行，但他们也
pipelines so that you can do a series of
管道，这样就可以做了一系列的
them just one cycle apart the only
他们只是一个周期相隔只有
different ones that are tis you'll
不同的人是那朵你会
notice the division is both very slow
注意分工都非常慢
and it's not pipelines and division is a
这不是管道和分裂是
very expensive operation on most
大多数非常昂贵的操作
machines relatively speaking so what I
机相对而言所以我
claim then is is these these
权利要求则是这些这些
characteristics then provide a limit on
特征则提供一个限制
how fast our program can run our
如何快速我们的程序可以运行我们的
original program in that I have a series
原计划中，我有一个系列
of multiplications for example of
乘法例如的
integers here and this shows the code
这里整数，这显示了该代码
for it and the result of I need the
它和我的结果所需要的
result of one multiplication before I
以前我一个乘法的结果
can begin the next so there's a three
可以开始下一 所以有一个三
clock cycle volunteer and you'll see
时钟周期的志愿者，你会看到
that in fact my measurements all
其实我的所有测量
correspond to what I'm calling the
对应于我打电话是什么
latency bound of these machines which is
延迟约束这些机器这是
just based on how much time it takes
只是根据需要多少时间
from a beginning of an operation to the
从操作的开始到
end and the reason is we considered
结束， 原因是我们认为
diagram the computation being done by
图的由正在做计算
this program that it's doing a series of
这个程序，它做了一系列的
multiplications and I require the result
乘法和我需要的结果
of one multiplication before I can start
一个乘法 之前，我可以开始
the next in general if you look at this
接下来一般来说，如果你 看看这个
loop code it has to compute ECX the
循环代码它来计算ECX的
updated value of it before it can now
它的更新值之前，它 现在可以
start the next one and so that's why
开始下 一个，因此 这就是为什么
even though this I have a pipeline
即使这 我有一个管道
multiplier my program itself limits me
乘法器我的程序本身限制了我
to the sequential execution of all the
对所有的顺序执行
multiplies
乘
so let's see if we can't get beyond that
让我们看看，如果我们不能获得超出
bound that latency bound well there's a
约束，且势必延迟 以及有一个
fairly common technique that you might
相当普遍的技术，你可能
have heard of before that's called loop
听说以前这就是所谓的循环
unrolling and the idea of loop unrolling
展开和循环展开的想法
is just that you rather than executing
仅仅是你，而不是执行
one value within a loop you execute a
一环内的一个值，你执行
multiple one and so this code shows
多个单因此该代码所示
unrolling by two and what it says is I'm
由两个展开和它说什么 是我
going to step through this array two
进入 步骤通过这个 阵列中的两个
elements at a time and within each of
在时间和中的每个元素
the inner loop I'm going to combine the
内循环我要去结合
values from di and di plus one and I
从二和二加一的和我值
have to put in some extra code to finish
必须把一些额外的代码来完成
off what happens if the original rate
如果关闭则 按原费率会发生什么
was a von wenk but you get the idea and
是冯WENK，但你的想法 和
this idea I showed this code of of two
这个想法， 我表现出的两个验证码
but you could imagine this applying for
但你能 想象这个申请
different values of loop unrolling so
的循环展开这样的不同值
will this help us any well when I run it
这将有助于我们 任何好当我运行它
I get that the integer addition got a
我得到的是整数 加法得到了
little faster but the other ones didn't
快一点， 但其他的 人都没有
improve at all so this one is going
改善所有所以这一块是怎么回事
faster because basically the old code
更快，因为基本上都是旧代码
which is the overhead of the loop
这是 回路 的开销
indexing and incrementing was enough to
索引和增量足以
be slowing me down because it's already
放缓我失望，因为它已经
close to a clock cycle so I just managed
接近时钟周期，所以我只是管理
to knock that down to be at the latency
敲下来是 在等待时间
bound of this particular instruction but
束缚， 这特定的指令 ， 但
it didn't have the other ones because I
它没有其他的人，因为我
still have the sequential dependency in
仍然有顺序的依赖
order to get my new value of X I have to
为了得到我XI的新价值有
first do one computation and then view
首先做一个计算，然后查看
the other before I can begin another one
另外 之前，我可以开始一个又一个
but this shows me the way I could make a
但是这显示了我，我可以做一个方式
very very small change and change
非常非常小的改变和变化
performance fairly dramatically what if
性能相当显着什么，如果
I take these parentheses and shift them
我把这些括号内将它们转移
to the right
向右
would that make any difference of and lo
这会让和LO任何区别
and behold yet you find that and I'll
不料但你会发现 ，我会
call that transformation unrolling by to
调用改造展开的，以
computing a one element at a time I'll
同时 我会 计算一个元素
talk about that in a minute but I'll use
谈论在 一分钟内 ，但我会用
this lowercase a to say I've done an
这小写字母a说我做的
associate ivities formation and you see
联想ivities形成，你会看到
all of a sudden my time's dropped in
突然我的时间的锐减中
half for these three cases so
一半这三种 情况等等
something's going on and so let's see
事情是怎么回事 ，并 让我们看看
why that is and now I'll introduce it
这是为什么，现在我就为大家介绍它
and so if I take my picture from before
所以，如果我把 我的照片从之前
and think about what those computations
， 想想 这些 计算
in PI you'll see that right now I've
在PI，你会看到，现在 我已经
changed the structure of the computation
改变计算的结构
so that I'm hair-wise combining each
让我的头发明智结合各
element of pair of elements of the array
对所述阵列的元件中的元件
and then accumulating those into the
然后累加这些成
overall computation so I've actually
总体计算 ，所以我实际上已经
that shifting of the parentheses
括号的那个变速
fundamentally changed how I'm doing my
从根本上改变了我 怎么 做我
computation and you can see now that
计算你 现在可以看到
this critical path which is what
这 正是这个关键路径
determines in this case the the
确定在这种情况下 的
performance limitation just got shorter
性能限制刚刚短
by a factor of two and that's why I'm
由两个因素， 这就是为什么我
now running twice as fast for for the
现在运行两次为快
operations not for integer addition but
操作不是整数加法，但
for the other three operations I've cut
其他三个业务我剪
by a factor or two just by that shift
通过只是这种转变的一个因素或两个
now there is some good news and bad news
现在有一些好 消息 和坏消息
here the good news is if this is integer
这里的好消息是，如果这是整
arithmetic we know already you know that
算术我们已经知道 你知道
two's complement arithmetic is
补算术
associative and commutative so it really
联想和交换这 的确让
doesn't matter for both multiplication
不要紧对乘法
and addition so it really doesn't matter
和另外所以它其实并不重要
what order I combine these elements and
什么顺序我结合这些元素 和
I'm going to get the exact same answer
我要 得到确切的答案一样
no matter what but you also saw
不管是什么，但你也看到了
voting point that's not the case so with
投票 点并非如此所以用
floating point that shift shifting these
浮点这种转变移位这些
parentheses because of rounding
由于四舍五入的括号
possibilities and even potentially
可能性和甚至可能
overflow you might get different values
溢出你可能会得到不同的值
results from these computations but then
从这些计算，但 随后 的结果
again if you think about you know is
再次，如果你认为你知道的 是
that really going to happen
真的要发生
chances are no that it's not really
机会是不，这不是真的
going to affect the outcome of your
会影响 结果 的
program but it's enough of a change that
程序但它足以改变的那
most C compilers the most compilers
大多数 C编译器的大多数编译器
period will not make any change that
期间将不会进行任何更改，
changes associativity because they're
变化的关联性，因为他们是
very conservative when it comes to
当涉及到非常保守
floating points so that's something you
浮点所以这是你的东西
as an application programmer has to have
作为应用程序的程序员必须 有
to know well enough is this a valid can
要知道不够好， 这是 一个有效的CAN
I do this transformation without messing
我做这个转变不会弄乱
things up and now what I'll say is now
事情了， 现在我会说是现在
there's a new set of bound
这有一组新的绑定
so abounding what would appear to be
如此丰富 似乎 什么 是
sort of the best you can do based on
排序的最好的，你可以做基于
some constraint in the program and
一些约束在节目中和
before it was saying well the latency
有人说很好的延迟之前
the total time through a given for a
通过的总时间为给定的
given operation was abound and now I say
给定的操作是比比皆是，现在我说
well there's an even more fundamental
以及还有一个更基本的
bound which I'll call the throughput
结合我称之为吞吐量
bound which is just based on I only have
这只是基于我只有绑定
so much Hardware out there and I can
如此多的硬件在那里，我可以
only a pump it so fast so for example
只有泵这么快 ，所以例如
these two that the throughput bound is 1
这两个界定所述吞吐量是1
because I only have that actually
因为我只有实际
becomes limited by the requirement that
变成被要求的限制在于
I'm having to read from memory and I
我在从内存和I阅读
have two different load units oh no I'm
有 两种不同的 负载单位哦，不，我
sorry I only have one multiplier for
对不起， 我只有一个乘法器
integers in one for addition the
在一个整数加法的
throughput bound for these two actually
吞吐量开往这两个实际上
is just 1/2 because it turns out there's
只是1/2， 因为 它原来有
some odd part of the hardware design
硬件 设计 的一些奇怪的一部分
that has two floating point multipliers
有两个浮点乘法器
but only one floating point adder and
但只有一个浮点加法器和
we'll see that we can actually make this
我们会看到 ，我们 实际上 可以 使这个
multiplication code run faster than
乘法代码的运行速度比
addition code
附加码
and over here again my limit will be
并在这里再次我的极限会
that I only have to load units and I
我只需要 加载的单位和我
have to be and I have to read for every
必须要和我要读 的每
element I'm computing I have to be
元素我计算我必须
reading one element from memory so I
从存储器中读出的一个元件，所以我
can't get below that okay so but we saw
不能得到低于好了，但我们看到了
this transformation now is let us break
这种转变现在让我们休息
out of this latency limitation and get
这项延迟限制的，并得到
something closer to throughput
更接近于吞吐量
here's another technique that can be
这里的另一个技术，可以
used to again sort of get more
使用 排序 ，再次 获得更多的
parallelism going and I call this
并行去，我称之为
multiple accumulators the idea is let's
多个蓄电池的想法是，让我们
a imagine that we have the odd-numbered
一个假设有奇数
elements and the even-numbered element
元素和偶数元件
from the array and we can we can compute
从阵列中，我们可以，我们可以计算
separate sums or products of those two
单独的和或产品这两个的
sets of elements and then the very end
套元件中 ，然后将最末端
combine them together so this is another
他们结合在一起，这是另一种
form of an associativity transformation
的关联性变换 形式
they were changing the order in which we
他们正在改变的顺序我们
combine things together it's just that
结合东西放在一起它只是
we're doing it in the suit of odd-even
我们正在做的奇偶的西装
manner or in general every ice value if
在一般每冰值，如果方式或
we do it by some by some parameter I and
我们做 一些通过 一些参数 我和
it has the same issues that if it's
它具有相同的问题， 如果它是
integer arithmetic it fine if it's
整数运算，如果罚款是
floating-point there's a risk of
浮点有风险
changing the behavior of the program but
改变 程序 的 行为 ，但
you'll see that again we get a cutting
你会看到 ， 我们 再次 获得了切割
in half here and a little bit below one
在这里一半以下 一个 一点点
for integer addition and again we can
整数加法和再次，我们可以
think of it by looking at these pictures
通过 看这些图片把它
of what are the what gets computed and
什么是在什么获取计算 和
you see what we're doing is we're
你看到我们正在做的是我们
computing here all the even numbers even
这里所有的计算甚至 偶数
numbered elements being combined and
被组合编号的元素和
here all the odd ones and the very end
这里所有的奇数者和尽头
we're combining those together and so we
我们结合这些一起，所以我们
can generalize this if we can unroll by
可以概括这一点，如果我们可以通过展开
a factor of K of L and we can accumulate
升K的因素，我们可以积累
K results in parallel and then we can
ķ导致平行，然后我们可以
use various values of L and K for in
用于以L和K的各种值
general LSB a multiple of ket
一般 LSB KET 的倍数
and so you run it out and you can get
所以你运行它，你可以 得到
for floating-point multiply you can
浮点乘法即可
actually get it down almost to this
实际上它弄下来几乎是这个
throughput bound of 0.5 this is
吞吐量将结合的0.5，这是
incorrect this is integer addition I
不正确，这是整数加法我
should say in tradition you can again
应该说，传统可以再次
get it down to around 0.5 and in general
得到它下降到大约0.5 和一般
by sort of picking the best parameters I
通过排序挑选最好的参数我的
can get very close to the throughput
可以得到非常 接近吞吐量
found of this processor so I've been
发现这个处理器的 ，所以我一直
able to take something remember
能够把一些东西记
originally was 20 clock cycles than 10
原本是20个时钟周期比10
and now I'm getting it down to one or
现在我得到它归结为 一个或
fewer clock cycles per illness so now
所以现在每疾病更少的时钟周期
just as the final step is okay is that
就像 最后一步是好的是 ，
as good as it go actually know you
好， 因为它真正去认识你
remember when I talked about
记得当我谈到
floating-point I mentioned that there's
浮点 我提到有
the special set of registers that are on
特殊 寄存器组是上
x86 that we're called xmm registers on
86，我们正在呼吁 XMM寄存器上
the sharp machines and now that has well
锋利的机器 ，现在有好
this newer generation has something
这种新一代有事
called ymm registers which have the
这些都是所谓的ymm寄存器
feature being twice as big as xmm
特征是两倍大XMM
registers so in particular these
特别是 这些寄存器，这样
registers are are 32 bytes long and
寄存器是32个字节长 和
there's a new version coming out within
有内走出一个新版本
a year or something they call a DX 512
一年 的东西，他们称之为DX 512
where the register is 512 bits so that's
其中寄存器是512位，这样的
256 sites
256个网站
long no it's to 512
长期没有它 512
get 64 bytes write 64 bytes there will
获得64个字节写64个字节会有
be twice as big as these and as I
是两倍大，因为这些和我
mentioned before you can think of these
之前提到的，你 可以认为 这些
as a way of operating on 32 individual
作为 32个单独 操作的一种方式
characters for I can treat them as
字符，我可以把它们作为
floating point and we saw before that
浮点 和我们之前看到的那个
you nowadays the regular floating point
您现在的常规浮点
makes use of Ceuta the low order for a
利用 休达的低位 为 的
bytes of these registers but there's
这些寄存器的字节，但有
also instructions called vector addition
也说明称为向量加法
where one instruction has the effect of
其中一个指令具有的效果
doing eight floating-point additions at
做8浮点加法的
once
一旦
unload data and on double precision the
卸载数据和双精度的
counterpart does four of them at once on
对方做他们四人在上一次
these and the that hardware is there
这些和硬件是有
it's just sitting there waiting to use
它只是坐在那里等待使用
and it seldom gets fired up to really
它很少被解雇了，真正
make use of it but so that floating
利用它，但是，这样的浮动
point multiplier that can do a 40 point
点乘数，可以做一个 40个 点
multiplication in three clock cycles and
乘法在三个时钟周期 和
it's fully pipeline can actually do
这是完全管线实际上可以做
eight floating point multiplications in
8次浮点乘法中
parallel and pipelines in three clock
平行和管道中的三个时钟
cycles
周期
and as I mentioned the sharp machine has
正如我所提到的 尖锐机具有
an earlier version where the numbers are
早期版本， 其中数字
half of these so it can do for single
其中一半，因此它可以为单一的做
precision or two double precision at
精度或两个双 精度在
once and if I write code that uses that
一次，如果我写的代码，它使用
what I call vector code then you can see
我所说的矢量代码，那么你 可以看到
I can drop by a factor of about four
我可以约四倍下降
across the board here and make it run
这里整个董事会，并使其运行
much faster so this 0.06 is really
更快所以这0.06是真的
0.0625 right it's doing 16 operations
0.0625 右它做 16个操作
per clock cycle on that and can't quite
每对时钟周期，并且不能 很
hit the vector throughput bound but in
打约束矢量吞吐量但是在
general making this thing run much
一般制作这个 东西跑得
faster and so the people really worry
更快， 所以人们真正担心
about and you can imagine these
关于你能想象这些
instructions were introduced for things
说明书介绍的东西
like video processing image processing
像的视频处理 的图像处理
of sound sort of signal processing where
的声音 种类的信号 处理，其中 的
a performance really matters how fast
性能真正重要的速度有多快
you can display an image how fast you
你能多快显示图像您
can rotate something you know how fast
可以旋转的东西，你知道有多快
you can perform graphics makes a big
您可以执行图形会产生很大的
difference in video games are one of the
在视频游戏中的差异是一个
big drivers but even for other
大驱动程序，但即使是其他
operations you might do on images and so
你可能会 在图像等做业务
these instructions were really designed
这些指令被真正 设计
to do it and people write code for those
做到这一点， 人们编写代码的那些
kind of applications get pretty good at
样的 应用程序 变得非常 擅长
writing code in a way that they can do
在某种程度上，他们可以做写代码
this vector ID what's called vectorizing
这个载体ID什么所谓的矢量化
and unfortunately so the Intel compiler
可惜所以英特尔编译器
will actually automatically do some of
实际上会自动做一些
this for you a GCC they attempted to
这个给你 ，他们试图将GCC
implement it and it didn't work very
实现它并没有 很努力
well so I think they discontinued it it
好，所以我想他们停止它，它
turns out there's a web aside so this is
原来有一个网络搁置，这是
on the web from the books web page that
从书本网页的web上
describes how to do this programming if
如果 说明如何 做到这一点编程
you're interested there's extensions to
你有兴趣有扩展
GCC they're very funky really weird
GCC 他们很时髦很奇怪
stuff but you can write code that then
的东西，但你可以写代码 ， 然后
will get compiled down to make use of
会被编译到利用
these kind of instructions and that's
这些类型的指令，这就是
how I did it and how I got these
我是如何做到 这一点，我是如何得到这些
performance
性能
results okay so that shows you if you
结果还好 ， 所以 如果你 将告诉 您
really want to and but that's very
真想 和但这是非常
machine specific that will only work on
该机的具体只会工作，上
well you have to you can actually tune
那么你有你其实可以调
it so it's easy to compile it to go
它，所以它很容易编译它去
between different machines but it's
不同的机器，但它之间的
still a fairly specific and very
仍然是一个相当具体， 很
specific to GCC in fact so that sort of
具体到GCC事实上， 这样的排序
shows you though if you really want to
显示你但如果你 真的想
push it what you can do now let's uh get
推你现在能做的，让我们呃得
back to one of the things I told you
回的 事情 之一 ，我告诉你
about how you can if you think of your
你如何 可以，如果你认为你的
program as a very long linear sequence
程序作为一个很长的线性序列
of instructions then the thing is trying
指令那么事情是试图
to grab as many of those and pull them
抓住尽可能多的那些 ，和他们拉
apart as fast as it can but of course
除了尽可能快，因为它可以 ，但当然
you know your program is actually
你知道你的程序 实际上 是
typically a loop and there aren't many
通常一个循环，并没有很多的
instructions in that loop so how is it
在循环指令，因此是怎么回事
turning that into a linear sequence
该转动成线性序列
well that relies on an idea of how do
以及依靠的是如何做的想法
you handle branches so typically the
你处理分支因此通常
program or fetching a head grabbing
程序或取出一个头敛
instructions and it will come to a
说明它会来一个
branch instruction a conditional jump of
分支指令的条件跳转
some sort and there is a dilemma because
某种并且有一个难题，因为
in general this branch could either I'm
一般这个分支既可以 我
sorry could either be taken meaning it
抱歉， 既可以采取意味着它
will go to the branch target or it could
会去转移目标 ，也可能
do it called fall through meaning it it
做到这一点，通过这意味着它叫秋天
the test fails and so it just continues
测试失败，所以它只是 继续
execution and there's no way a priority
执行，有没有办法优先
to know what will happen these can often
要知道会发生什么，这些往往能
be data dependent and so the way this is
依赖数据等的方式，这是
handled on a modern processor is by
处理 在现代处理器是
doing what's known as branch prediction
做了所谓的分支预测
which is essentially just guess which
这是本质上只是猜测哪些
ways this branch is going to go is going
该方法分支要去会
to be taken or not and you predict and
要采取与否，你预测和
then you start executing along the
然后你开始沿执行
predicted direction but do it in a way
预测方向，但这样做 的方式
that if you make a mistake you haven't
如果你 犯了一个错误 ，你有没有
caused irreparable harm to the program
造成不可弥补的损害 的程序
and we'll see what that means so what
我们将看到这 意味着 什么 还等什么
really happens then is up here there's a
真正发生的事就是在这里有一个
lot of logic that
大量的逻辑是
trying to suck out instructions and then
试图吸出的指令，然后
there's a branch unit that being
还有，作为一个分支单元
basically coming along later and saying
后来基本上沿着来，说
yeah you're okay you predicted that
是啊你 没事你预测
correctly so you can keep going or it
正确地这样 你就可以继续下去，或者
will throw up a flag and say oh wait a
将抛出一个标志，并且说，哦等待
minute stop your misprediction you
分钟停止你的预测错误，你
mispredicted this branch way back 100
错误预测 该分支路回100
clock cycles ago it's not that long ago
时钟周期以前是不是很久 以前
but some number of clock cycles ago
但一些数量的时钟周期的前
you've got to fix it and so so the hand
你要修复它，所以这样的手
way of jumps then becomes more a case of
然后跳跃的 方式 变得更加的情况下，
of guessing up here and then either
猜测在这里，然后要么
confirming or denying that guess down
确认或否认猜测下降
below so in general then if you it will
下面所以一般这时如果它会
predict it one way and begin executing
预测的一种方式，并开始执行
so imagine for example in a loop like
所以可以想象，例如在如环
I've shown you that you predict that the
我向您展示 您预测，
branch will be taken but you'll go back
分支将被 采用，但你会回去
to the start of the loop again that's
在循环的开始再次这是
actually a pretty good guess it's a good
实际上是一个相当不错的猜测这是一个好
guess extolled you hit the end of the
猜赞美你打的结束
loop but let's just guess that way and
循环，但我们只是猜测方式
so the program will just keep guessing
所以程序将只保留 猜测
that the branch will be taken and and by
该分支将被采用，并通过
that means by all those guesses
这意味着所有这些猜测
basically create this long linear
基本上建立 这个长的直线
sequence of instructions that can be
指令序列， 可以是
pulled in and executed and in general
被引用，并执行与一般
some of them will be fetched and some of
他们中的一些将获取和 一些
them will actually have done the
他们实际上已经做了
operations that are called for in the
这是在要求操作
instruction and then what happens is if
指令，然后发生的事情是，如果
if the flag goes up they say no this was
如果标志上升，他们说没有，这是
invalid then what will happen is it will
无效，那么会发生什么是 它 会
go back and cancel all the instructions
回去并取消所有的指令
that have been fetched and executed and
已 被获取 和执行，
the way it does that is you'll notice
顺便它确实是 你会 发现
not all these instructions only modify
不仅 所有这些 指令修改
registers and it has multiple copies of
注册并拥有 的 多个 副本
all the registers going back these are
所有的寄存器回去这些都是
the registers these are the values that
寄存器这些是值该
I'm sure of
我敢肯定的
these are
这些是
speculative values appending updates to
推测值追加更新
them and so when it comes time to cancel
他们所以当谈到时间取消
it just cancels out all those pending
它只是 取消了所有 这些待发
updates and goes back to values that
更新并回到 该值
it's certain of question the there is a
它的某些问题的 存在
big block they call the register
大块他们所谓的寄存器
renaming unit which is sort of multiple
重命名单元，其排序多的
copies of all the registers as they get
因为他们 得到 的所有寄存器的副本
accumulated it has many more it will
累积有更多的它会
typically have several hundred reg of
通常有几百reg的
these sort of virtual registers to keep
这些类型的虚拟寄存器，以保持
pending copies to the actual registers
未决复制到实际寄存器
it does it stores you know here's the
它它存储知道这里是的
old value here's the first update here's
这里原值是这里的第一次更新是
the second update here's the third and
这里的第二个更新的第三和
it keeps track of all that you can
它使所有的曲目， 你可以
imagine why this is not a something you
想象为什么这不是你的东西
learn in a one semester course right
学习一个学期的课程 的权利
that to keep track of all those
该跟踪所有这些
different things flying by and make sure
不同的东西飞过 ，并确保
that it works is a pretty tricky
它的工作原理 是一个相当棘手
business
商业
but the conceptually it's a pretty
但在概念上它是一个非常
simple idea that it just races off does
简单的想法 ，它 只是比赛确实关闭
a lot of things based purely on
纯粹基于 很多东西
speculation and then only if it makes a
投机，然后仅当它是一个
mistake it goes oh it sort of rolls back
错误不言而喻 哦 ，它像是回滚
to as if it had only execute up to a
就好像它仅 执行到一
certain point and then it moves forward
某一点，然后 向前 移动
and starts in going the correct way so
并开始在去所以正确的方法
and and so and it can get away with this
并因此， 它可以 逃脱这个
it's very interesting and tricky stuff
这是非常有趣的和棘手的东西
but you remember we talked early in the
但你还记得我们在前期谈
course about the difference between
当然有关的区别
using conditional moves and conditional
使用条件和移动条件
jumps to implement conditional
跳到实施条件
operations and conditional moves can
运算和条件可移动
take place totally within the structure
采取完全 的体系中的地位
of this pipeline but a conditional jump
这 条管线，但条件跳转
if it's an unpredictable branch the
如果它是一个不可预知的分支
problem is it might go off executing and
问题是，它可能会熄灭并执行
make do a lot of wasted work but even
让做了很多工作，浪费，但即使的
worse than when it gets back and has to
比 当它回来，并有 恶化
restart it takes a while to sort of fill
重新启动需要一段时间 来 排序的补
up all the
把所有的
the buffers in the system and get the
在系统中的缓冲区，并获得
whole thing running at full steam ahead
在开足马力运行整个事情
so that kind of finishes up then the the
这样那样的结束了，则该
way I describe it is first of all don't
这样，我形容它首先是做不
do anything stupid
做任何愚蠢的事
even and stupid is probably too strong a
甚至和愚蠢的可能是 太强
word don't do sort of keep in mind
字不做 那种牢记
there's certain things that you should
有一些事情，你 应该
as a programmer be doing all the time
作为一个程序员做所有的时间
and they're not obvious perhaps and then
而且他们 并不明显也许 再
begin thinking about tuning and getting
开始思考调整和越来越
some instruction level parallelism and I
一些指令级并行和我
describe it as for the machine but as I
把它描述 为对机器，但我
said pretty much all processors nowadays
说几乎 所有时下的处理器
it's a class of machines and so these
这是一类机等等这些
general techniques will work that those
通用技术将工作的那些
ideas of changing the associativity will
改变关联的想法会
work whether it's you know the ARM
工作无论是你知道 ARM
processor built into my cell phone or
处理器内置到我的手机或
the x86 processor built into your laptop
x86处理器内置到您的笔记本电脑
or one of the shark machines they all
或者鲨鱼的一台机器都
have the same general of implementation
有执行相同的一般
structures so these techniques will work
结构使这些技术将工作
across across all of them ok that'll do
横跨所有他们 确定 这会做
it for today
今天它